transitchicago.com 2019-04-21

# CTA Privacy Policy - CTA

This statement provides the Chicago Transit Authority’s privacy policy on information that is collected through this website and use of that information.

#### See also:

## **In General**

The CTA may use the information it collects for management and promotion of CTA and other regional transit services and fare media. We will not sell or disclose your information for any other purpose without explicit consent, unless there is a legal requirement for such disclosure. To the extent that the CTA discloses information to third-party contractors or other regional transportation agencies for the management and promotion of CTA and other regional transit services, or to administer fare media programs, those third parties will be required to follow this privacy policy.

## **Information Collected and Processed During Your Visit to This Website**

The CTA is the sole owner of the information collected on this site at [transitchicago.com](http://transitchicago.com/). The CTA collects information from its customers at several different points on the website. By using our services and accessing our site, you are consenting to the information collection and use practices described in this statement, as modified from time to time by us without further notice.

The information collected on this site is stored and processed by a third party vendor named americaneagle.com.  Terms and conditions on how americaneagle.com handles the information can be found here: <https://www.americaneagle.com/legal/privacy>.

## **Personal Information**

We collect several different types of information on our site. We collect personal information, defined as information that can be used to identify you individually, such as your name, address and telephone number, only if you submit the information to us, such as when contacting us. CTA employees who have access to your personal information do so only for legitimate business purposes, such as when looking into or responding to something you have contacted us for, and they will endeavor to protect the confidentiality of your personal information. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

## **Technical Information**

We automatically collect and store technical information about your visit to our site including: (1) the name of the domain and host from which you access the Internet; (2) the type of browser software and operating system used to access our site; (3) the date and time you access our site; and (4) the pages you visit on our site. The technical information collected does not personally identify you.

The following information explains in more detail the different forms of personal and technical information and how we may collect and use that information.

## **Location Information**

In order to provide location-based information, such as a list of nearby transit stops, our site may request that your browser or device provide us with your rough or precise location. You will be asked to give consent to our browser to collect location information. We may also aggregate anonymous data to better understand how people are using these location-enhanced services and later improve those services. 

## **E-mail Address**

If you send us an e-mail with questions or comments or if you provide your e-mail address when ordering CTA merchandise or subscribing to receive notifications of newly-available information regarding pertinent CTA transit services by e-mail or wireless-enabled device, the CTA may use your e-mail address and other personal information provided by you (defined in Personal Information section) included in your correspondence to improve the content of our website, to provide you with pertinent information regarding CTA transit services, or to respond to your correspondence. Your e-mail address will be used only to deliver the requested information unless you agree to additional e-mail notifications. If you provide your e-mail address to receive notifications such as service alerts, the CTA will use your e-mail address to send you the type of information for which you provided it.

## **Subscriptions**

You may subscribe to receive information from CTA, such as information about planned or unplanned events that affect transit service delivered through the CTA Updates service, or to receive news about CTA and our services. To unsubscribe from these services, follow the instructions at the bottom of messages we send or visit our “unsubscribe” page on transitchicago.com and following the instructions noted there.

## **Surveys**

From time to time, the CTA may conduct online surveys that customers will be invited to complete on a voluntary basis. Unless you expressly agree otherwise, information collected through the surveys will be used only for the purpose of marketing or planning CTA services. We may contact you if we need more information regarding your survey response.

## **Children's Privacy**

CTA does not knowingly solicit or collect personal information through its website from children. If at any time CTA learns that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personal information online, it will take all reasonable measures necessary to remove such information from its databases and not use such information for any purpose except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others, or as required by law.

## **Employment-Related Information**

If you are interested in CTA employment you can [apply online](https://www.transitchicago.com/careers) and submit information regarding past work experience. This information will be used only for evaluating an applicant's qualifications for a position with CTA. Employment-related information is handled by a third party vendor named Oracle. Oracle processes the personal information you provide. Oracle’s terms and conditions are found here: <https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/index.html>

## **Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that a website can place on your computer's hard drive to, for example, remember preferences or information about what you do on a site, or make it easier to remember you on future visits. The cookie information can then be transmitted back to the site on future visits. You may set your web browser to warn you whenever a site attempts to place a cookie on your computer or refuse to accept cookies. CTA may use cookies collected during your visit to this site for the purpose of facilitating your use of our site and for maintaining statistics concerning use of our site that will help us make improvements. Technical information collected by cookies will not be linked to your personal information and information about other sites you visit is not collected by CTA.

## **Profile**

We store technical information that we collect through cookies and log files to create a general profile of our customers. The profile information is used to improve the content of the site, to perform a statistical analysis of use of the site, and to enhance use of the site. Technical information stored in a profile will not be linked to your personal information.

## **Links & Embedded Content**

This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website. Please be aware that this website contains links to other sites and content embedded from other sites, such as YouTube. CTA is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our customers to use care when they leave our site or submit information to other sites and to read the privacy statements of each website that collects personally identifiable information.

## **Notification of Changes**

CTA reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy without notice. If we change our privacy policy, we will post a new statement on our site 30 days before the changes become effective and will change the date indicated at the bottom of the statement. Therefore, we encourage you to check the date of our privacy policy statement whenever you visit this site for any updates or changes. Please see our [Terms of Use](https://www.transitchicago.com/terms) for a more detailed legal explanation of our general online policies.

## **How to Contact Us?**

If you have any questions about our privacy policy statement or our use of your information you can e-mail us at [webmaster@transitchicago.com](mailto:webmaster@transitchicago.com).

## **Canceling Notifications or Subscriptions**

You may cancel your receipt of notifications or subscriptions at any time.  It may take up to 30 days for the cancellation of notifications or subscriptions to go into effect.  With regard to subscriptions, please unsubscribe from each subscription to which you subscribe.

## **Protecting Your Information**

We do not sell personal information, aggregate anonymous data or technical information to any third party.  We engage third party service providers to perform the services we provide, and the third party service providers are identified here. Each third party service provider has its own privacy policy. Please follow the links provided to review the privacy policies.

## **Special Notice**

Effective Date of this version of CTA's Privacy Policy: December 30, 2018.

_Use of this site signifies your acceptance of Chicago Transit Authority Website Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy._
